It is time today.
We're going to do the S-tier list for your
landing page, also
known as a sales page. For some of you,
you may even call it a website.
Just before we begin,
the important thing here is,
for so many of you out there,
you don't need to grow your following.
You don't need to grow your email list.
If you can just improve the conversions on
this page from 1% to
2%, that doubles your income,
doubles the amount of clients,
no extra effort.
And I have put together a free resource on
the anatomy of a landing page.
You can get a link for
that in the description. Let's begin.
Starting off,
we have a term called above-the-fold
clarity.
In essence,
when you land on a landing page,
there's only so much you can see
in that very screen without having to
scroll.
On mobile,
it looks very different to desktop.
We call this above the fold.
The fold is that bottom part you can't see
under.
This goes in as an A tier,
because it's important that
when people land,
they know exactly what they're getting.
We see this again on social media, even
if you go on someone's YouTube.
If you can land on their YouTube above the
fold with the videos that are there and
the title and the bio,
do we know what this person does?
Same on an Instagram.
When we go to the bio,
without having to scroll
and look at their content, can we
get a snapshot of what that person does?
First impressions.
You wouldn't go to a bloody first date
looking like a scruff, so don't do it on
your landing page either. Now, dark mode.
Choosing light fonts and dark backdrops
is a trend that we've started to see.
The majority of users on YouTube
are now using dark mode,
and this again slots in
as an A tier. Look at things like Discord.
When looking at readability,
when looking at things like people not
wanting bright
screens before bed, I believe
that it's just important
that the majority of us
look for a dark backdrop,
just to make it that bit kinder on the
eyes.
Now, the next element is called urgency
or scarcity.
Only four spots left.
I'm looking for five men over
30 looking to lose three to seven
kilograms of body— stop.
This goes in at D tier.
We know the scarcity's not real.
When you say you've got four slots left,
are you kidding me?
If you had 10 people come
and apply for whatever it
is you're selling, you'd take
them. So stop lying. Why are you lying?
Scarcity, when faked,
often just looks like desperation.
You're lucky you didn't end up in E tier
with that.
So those of you with your fake countdown
timers, only three slots left, we know
it's bollocks. Moving on to the next bit.
One clear promise.
What I call this is,
as soon as we land on the page,
that first heading
title,
what is that promise it's giving us?
That goes in at S tier,
the very first thing to be an S-tier
component. That first sentence
is so important, and
when it comes to A/B split
testing,
that's the first thing I would change.
So once you've got your landing page set
up, maybe make three, four variations
changing that title.
How to quit smoking forever.
How to improve your jujitsu gas tank in
under 90 days.
How to squat three times body weight
without taking steroids. Whatever it is.
As soon as we see that title,
we should know exactly what it
is we're being sold.
If you get that right, the rest is easy.
Testimonials,
I'm going to put in at B tier.
The reason for this being,
it's very apparent that all of us have
hyper responders.
I've got over 1,000 people in my
mentorship, 15, 20 of
them have done exceptionally well.
So they're the ones that
are always going to be found on your
landing page for
testimonials.
The same with fat loss coaches,
the same with entrepreneurs, whatever
it is. You're just skimming the top,
and people know that, and they know
that when
they land on your page.
So with testimonials,
the reason they get a B tier is
because there is some impact from having
them.
Proof that you know what you're on about,
but at the same time, they don't have the
effectiveness of other tactics
that we're going to get onto in this
video.
So it gets a B tier, mid tier.
Don't lose sleep over your testimonials
because half
the people reading them don't even believe
them.
This is why where even with Nutonic,
I butt heads with the other people in the
team. I say, "Look,
we shouldn't have scripted testimonials of
people saying it's
the best drink in the world." We should
actually be putting out content of people
saying, "Didn't like this flavor.
I think citrus tastes like shit.
However,
felt great taking it." More believable.
I used a travel brand called Nomadic.
Excellent suitcases.
Sent me some for Chris Williamson's tour
last year. Now, the zip broke on one.
I messaged them, they sent me one,
and they didn't just send me one,
they sent me a
bum bag. Or a fanny pack,
if you're in America.
So if you were to ask me to do an advert
on Nomadic, I would say, "The cases are
well-built, but they're not imperfect.
I had one a year ago
and the zip broke." So they go,
"Oh my God, why is this guy
chatting rubbish about our brand?"
However, all I had to do
was manage the company,
and they didn't just resolve it,
they put me in a net better position.
Thank you, Nomadic.
Advertising we can believe.
Believability is a massive thing.
Now, B tier,
you're not alone because we're going to
add another one to you now.
We have price anchors.
What I mean by this is
when we have a price,
sometimes we can put another price next to
it to make that price look better or to
look worse.
I actually had one of these backfire on me
recently where to make the
mentorship look cheaper,
I did a one-to-one offer, $12,500,
10 weeks
of calls.
I had to take it offline because too many
people were buying it.
It was there as an anchor. I was like,
"Oh, I hope no one buys that because it'll
make the other thing look cheaper." Did me
in.
I made loads of money,
but I'm doing a lot of calls at the
moment.
That's what I'm saying.
It gets a B tier because we shouldn't have
to have
tomfoolery with our pricing just to make
an impact.
For me, you're probably thinking,
why did you have it then, James?
I'm always testing things myself.
So I wanted to know,
when we implement the price anchor,
how much of an uptick do
we see in sales for the ticket program?
I haven't got the analytics on it yet.
The second I have it, you can have it.
The majority of the things
that I'm trying, whether
or not having someone DMs in
the business Instagram page
or whatever it is, I'm trialing
and testing so I can
actually give you real answers on real
things.
But the price anchor, let's say B tier.
It's not essential.
It could be a good idea.
It could be something
that levels up your sales, but it
also could hinder them.
Which brings me on to the first E
tier, the time delay timer. Oh,
only 19 hours
left. Or the convenient one, that
when you land on the page,
it says 23 hours,
59 minutes, and 59 seconds,
and you're like, "Oh, no,
I best buy because I might
not be on time this time tomorrow." Hit
refresh, the timer starts again.
You look like a dickhead. There
is this Americanization of these, "Hey,
man, get
in now with all these free things.
You can get this cookbook for
$0.
Real value, $499." Whoa, bro,
no one's ever paid $499 for a
cookbook. Relax. Get back in your box,
you little cunt.
But those time delay timers just look like
shit. We know it. You know it.
Fake scarcity. E tier.
Get it off your page. It's damaging.
Now,
to keep the time delay timers from getting
lonely, we got another one going
in at D tier, type forms.
The amount of you using type forms
where I read your page, I'm like,
"Oh my God, I'm ready to go.
I want to start." Boom. Application form.
Application form?
Why am I applying for what you sell?
It's not a sorority house, love.
Also,
why are you asking me for my name
and my email address when I just came from
your email marketing flipping campaign?
I'm ready to buy and I'm typing out a
form.
Type forms, tacky, rubbish, shit A.
When I'm ready to buy, I'm ready to buy.
If you slap me a form
when I'm ready to buy,
I'm going somewhere else.
It's time to talk about the money-back
guarantee. Where's it going? S tier.
The money-back guarantee isn't just for
your customer, that
is probably entitled to
their money back anyway if you
were to look at any of the consumer rights
laws, but
it's there for you.
Having a money-back guarantee gives you
the confidence in your
pitch,
and this is going to be the best massage
ball for alleviating
soreness of the medulla oblongata
or your money back.
Sometimes the money-back guarantee
is for you, not them.
And if offering a money-back guarantee
improves your sales by 30%, even
if you get a 5% refund rate,
that's completely fine.
And if you're getting over a 15% refund
rate, it's not care about your landing
page, your product
and your services need some work.
Sunny Jim.
Sometimes when you're on a landing page,
you get a pop-up, a little pop-up thing
coming up saying, "Oh,
give us your email address." We're going
to give this a D
tier. And although Eight Sleep do it,
and yes,
that was the video I did the other
day for Eight Sleep. Why
are you trying to obtain someone's email
address from a
landing page? Really,
if you do the process properly,
we should have put out
content on social media
and at some point got someone's email
address, then sent
them to the landing page from the email
address.
If you get in the habit of sending people
to the landing page without their email,
well,
they'll probably go through it once
and never come back.
The reason I give this a D tier
is merely because I would much rather you
had someone's email address in pocket
before sending them to your landing page.
A video autoplay with sound.
Give this a C tier.
I just don't think it's that important.
Although it's quite nice to see a video
autoplay, I think we should be giving
people the opportunity to determine
whether or not they want to watch the
video.
Because people landing on a landing page,
they come in different shapes and sizes.
Me, I'm a buyer. That car,
went to look at it, I'll buy it.
He was like, "Okay,
do you want to test drive it first?" "Go
on then." Audi RS6,
went in, I said, "I'll buy it." He goes,
"Do you not want to test drive it?" I go,
"Mate,
I've already made my mind up." He says to
me, the last person that bought an
RS6 off him said the exact same thing.
I'm always ready to go.
First house I ever looked at, bought it.
I am the type of person
that wants to send the money before you
ask for it.
Some people out there want to watch the
video.
Some people out there want to read the
text.
Some people out there don't want to watch
the video.
You are curating a landing page
that has something for everyone.
But the autoplay could then put a video in
someone's face that maybe just wanted to
read the text.
That's why it gets a C tier.
Mobile optimized layout. Oh, look at that.
It's my beautiful son riding a New Tonic
designed Rimowa around
the airport. It gets A tier,
and you're probably wondering why it
doesn't get S
tier. Well, the majority of people,
let's say 70% of people come through
mobile.
We can't give this S tier because we got
to appreciate a lot of people come
from desktop as well,
maybe up to one in three.
So although you should be putting all your
focus and effort into mobile
optimization, I also want tablet
and desktop optimization.
I do not want them looking shit because
three out of 10 is still a lot of people.
Branding fluff and logos
is going to get a D tier.
The reason for this,
sometimes I land on a landing page,
the top half
is your brand, your logo. No one cares.
The majority of you, no offense,
your logos look like shit,
and you seem to think
that strengthens your page. It doesn't.
Delete it.
Your promise of what you're going to do to
help someone, people care about that a
lot more than your shitty brand
that someone made for you on Fiverr.
Your logos, your taglines,
all of this shit does nothing for the
person on your
page because they only have one thing in
mind, and that thing in mind is them.
So get your branding
and your shitty logos away.
Put it on your fucking invoice
that you send them.
Now,
I would say this one goes in at C tier,
and this is your personal information.
And the reason I'm only giving this a C
tier is the majority of you shouldn't have
this on your page,
but then some of you should.
And what I mean by this is,
if you're a small creator,
if you're someone that's
been doing sales calls,
you're someone that really needs new
clients, just give
them your WhatsApp number.
Just give them your email address.
Just let them contact you direct.
And have your process
and where you may have
usually said,
"Let's do a sales call," just say,
"Drop me a text, drop me a
message." Make yourself accessible because
as a small account, that is one of your
unique selling points. I'll be honest,
I got the most nudes when my Instagram had
100,000 followers.
Now it's got 1.4 million, none.
I don't even get dick pics from random
creepy dudes on the internet.
I haven't had someone try
and buy my underwear off me for like four
years.
When your account gets big,
people think you're inaccessible.
So when you're a small account, use
that to your bloody benefit.
"Hey, here's my mobile number.
Give me a call." Rather than booking in
for a sales call on the 3rd of January at
4:00 PM for one
hour using Google Meets. "Hey,
here's my number. Drop me a call.
Sorry, mate,
couldn't get to yours with a client."
You've been on the landing page.
What is it you need help with?
"I just want to talk about pricing." Could
be a
voice note, whatever.
Gets a C tier because some of you should
and some of you
shouldn't. Social proof using screenshots.
I'm going to give this an A tier.
Whether that's a conversation
or a WhatsApp conversation with your
client, maybe
it's someone posting their wins in the
Discord. Such a great realistic thing.
Stripe,
if you're in the business to business,
taking a screenshot of your Stripe
goes a long way because you're showing
people, you're appealing to authority, and
there's something
that just feels genuine about a
screenshot.
We send screenshots to each other
and our friends. That's getting an A tier.
Now, an obvious offer, what it is,
why they need it, what they get.
If you make that clear
and easy to understand,
that's going in at S tier.
So many landing pages you get reading
through them, you're like,
"I don't know what
it is. I don't know what I get.
I don't know why I need it."
If you fundamentally
forget those things, you made a big,
big mistake. S tier.
Now, carousels and sliders
and images you can move around
and testimonials
you can move around, D tier.
I don't like the fact you're making people
work and
swipe to get more information.
The only direction people should be moving
in the
page is vertical.
They should be moving down the page like a
story.
What I don't want to confuse people
is an up and down motion,
a sideways motion.
The second we overwhelm someone,
they're gone.
The second we make things overcomplicated,
The second we disrespect someone's time by
making the bloody thing
not readable enough, they're gone.
Next up, pricing tables.
And these pricing tables
are going to go to B tier.
Now, the reason this isn't an A
or an S tier is merely
that sometimes these tables
can do more harm than good.
Some of us should have a flat rate for the
one price of
the one product we're trying to sell.
If we try and put too many products on a
landing page and too many pricing tables,
one, we can overwhelm people, two,
we can confuse them, but three,
we can run into
the territory where, hold on,
these different tiers should have had
their own
different sales funnels and systems.
Because if you've got something for $99
and something for $1,000,
that could be two
completely different people of an audience
with two completely different sets of
products with two completely different
sets of problems.
So for that reason,
we might have been better out building
different email
automations, different landing pages,
and different curated journeys to get that
person to buy.
It's going to be difficult
that the person right for 99 and
999 could be sold to on the right page.
And sometimes we can be a little bit lazy
with that by trying to get everything
into one page when they need separate
bloody pages. So it gets a B tier.
Good color contrast and button visibility.
Get in at A tier.
For your colors,
you can look at Adobe color palette wheel.
You can stick to the basics.
You can pick some nice colors,
but do not be
using like red and orange and black
and lime green.
Pick good basic colors.
Look at online palette generators.
Especially dudes out there.
You know what it's like growing up as a
boy.
You go downstairs, your mom
and your sister go,
"You can't wear that." You're like,
"Why not?" Blue and green,
never to be seen.
You're like,
"Who made that?" Girls just have a way of
knowing.
The way they get the palette colors with
the bedsheets together and the throw all
adds up. Get those colors nice. And
if you're not sure, ask a woman for
her advice. The button.
Research shows the button should be red,
but just have it
obvious and plain and easy to see.
And don't have like a baby blue
background and then a Kawasaki green ninja
bloody Buy Now button.
It looks abhorrent A tier for that.
Custom domain gets a B tier.
The reason it gets a B tier is it looks
good, but it's not essential.
Because these people
are going to be clicking a
hyperlink in the email,
or they're going to be clicking a
hyperlink from some kind
of chatbot or your socials.
At the end of the day,
they probably don't care all in
all that much, but at the same time,
it's quite important,
so it's ended up in B
tier for that. No one's,
"I'm not buying your stuff because you
didn't have a
custom domain." But at the same time,
if you can go to the effort, it just looks
better. B tier.
Using yourself as a hero image
when people land on the page, E
tier. What are you doing? What,
you think a picture of you benefits
them? What it is, why they need it,
what they get, why they should trust you.
A VSL, video sales letter.
Where have I ever said there should be a
picture of
you flipping with your top off
or whatever bullshit it is. E tier.
Get it out there.
The only thing worse than that
is stock images. Another E tier.
Get in there.
Stock images of people at a desk looking
frustrated.
Mate, this is your landing page. This
is important.
Going from 1% to 2%, double your money.
Why would you go onto Google Images
and pick an image of a random person,
which you
haven't even got the copyright to,
to try and bolster your sales page?
If an image of someone doing a certain
thing is that important,
take one yourself,
you lazy sod. Loading fast,
sub two seconds, give it a
B tier. It's important
that your stuff moves quick and
that people can load it.
If the page is taking too long,
they're gone.
But at the same time,
I wouldn't say it's a business critical
thing.
If it takes three seconds to load,
guess what?
You're probably going to be all right.
Blog posts or external links to socials,
E tier.
Remember,
we have a funnel moving in a certain
direction.
Socials, email, landing page, sale.
If you send someone to YouTube
or Instagram or your Twitter,
they're moving back up
the funnel in the wrong direction.
And the worst part is,
they go to YouTube to watch a video
and you're going, "Oh,
they might watch my channel." Yeah,
guess what?
When you watch a YouTube video,
there's 10 other videos there ready,
and they're
all going to be your competitors saying
the bloody same thing.
So you've sent them back up the funnel
from a sales page to YouTube.
They're now watching one of your
competitor's videos.
They're going to end up on their
competitor's landing page, and guess what?
They're not dumb enough to send people
back up the bloody funnel to go get
distracted. Stop it. It's stupid.
The landing page, one, one,
one thing we want, and that is to
click the Buy Now button.
Anything apart from that
is a bloody distraction.
Upsells and cross-sells, C tier. Yeah,
you've got multiple products, cool,
but again, you're just distracting people.
We don't want to see, "Oh, and
if you're interested in doing unicycle
lessons..."
Piss off, mate.
I came here for guitar lessons.
You're confusing me. I'm gone.
Embedded social feeds, D tier. Again,
giving anyone the opportunity
to go, "Oh, I didn't see
that on his Instagram." Boom,
back to the Instagram.
They're gone.
They've gone the wrong way up the funnel.
Sometimes it can sometimes look good
if you want to do an appeal to authority,
or let's say you're selling a course on
how to make viral videos.
You could show a video of yours that's
viral. But again, it's a D tier.
There are more important things
that belong on the landing page.
A nav bar with multiple links away from
the page, E tier.
About me, don't care.
Testimonials should be on the flipping
page, not up there in the nav bar.
Contact us.
All of this stuff, that
is indicative of a website,
not a landing page.
I don't want multiple things
that I can click on and get distracted.
If there's a nav bar,
it just goes to show you don't know how to
construct a
landing page. E tier. Get out. A VSL,
a video sales
letter that sits front and center
when we land on the page, S tier.
When I was dating back in the day,
I'd look, and if I
was to see someone's profile,
I'd always want to see a video of them
because you could tell so much about
someone
the second you see a video. When I
was personal training,
I'd get my clients to
send me a video because I could tell so
much about them.
If they sent me a video going, "Hi, James.
My name is Rose.
I train at home because the gym makes me
anxious." Cool, I know what Rose is like.
Other people are like, "Yo, mate,
it's Steve.
Thanks, yeah, basically, mate,
been running my own business,
got a little bit fat."
I knew so much about Steve. With a video,
some of these people, sure they've seen
you in socials.
Sure they've been reading your emails.
But sometimes it's just nice for you to
sit in front of them and go, "Yeah, so the
reason I made my business mentorship
was I've actually not been a personal
trainer
for the last 10 years.
I've been running online businesses.
So for that reason,
I thought why not take all these lessons
and sell them to you?"
Doesn't have to be over-edited. It
just needs to be like, "Look,
made this program.
If you don't love it,
you drop me an email,
send your money back." "Hey, it's
James, founder of NuTonic.
I don't expect you to believe me, but
if you try it and
you don't like it, drop me an email,
send your money back. It's that good.
Thank you so much for watching.
Look forward to seeing your email pop up
in my
inbox later,
and can't wait to get started." That's the
side that should come out
in the VSL. If you nail that, boom,
S tier. S tier is not alone.
Font and readability. Ed Lawrence
was telling me about someone in his
program that
increased their font size and, like,
17-folded their sales.
If the font's too small, gone.
If they can't read, gone.
Not everyone out there
is as young with as good eyesight as you,
my
pedigree chum. Some of us
are flipping blind, and
if we can't read it,
we're gone. Readability over everything.
Readability over everything. S tier,
up there.
If it's not easy to read, make it easier.
No one's ever going to get on your page
and go, "Oh, it's bloody too easy to read
that stuff." Don't make it more difficult
than it needs to be.
Make it clear and easy.
Which brings us on to hidden pricing.
If you're the type of person
that wants to jump on a sales call before
telling
people how expensive you are,
you're a snake. You're a fucking snake.
You should be proud of your pricing.
You should show it off.
Being expensive's fine.
You can go to Louis Vuitton.
You can go to Gucci.
You can go to Ferrari.
You can go to Porsche. Guess what?
The price is on the cars,
so you can make an informed decision.
Now, if people can't afford your stuff,
that's fine.
But they should at least know how much it
is so they can go away and budget.
Let's imagine I want to get my dog
lessons, right?
I go onto the local guy, find his page,
$1,000.
I go, "Wow, $1,000
is a lot for dog lessons." Then one day my
dog gets off the
lead, runs off,
doesn't come back for two hours.
I'm thinking the worst.
I'm going straight to
that guy's website and paying $1,000.
Because I have that anchor in my mind.
I know how much he costs.
I know where he is.
I know where I can get him.
Not everyone has to buy the second they do
it.
But if there's a level of ambiguity,
did I say that right?
To what is the pricing,
how much does it cost?
There's no difference here.
Put your pricing on your page.
Don't be a snake because you're just going
to try
and high pressure people into the call,
and then you suffer from your shitty
Typeform. "Oh, well, Sandra, you said
that if you didn't lose four kilograms in
the
next three months,
you'd look like a sack of potatoes at the
wedding.
Is that not true, Sandra?
Because as soon as I told you the price,
Sandra, you said
you couldn't afford it, but I thought
that you had a wedding to get in shape
for,
Sandra." You snakes, I hate you
when you do that.
Just show your damn pricing.
If any of you think you have a better
reason to hide your pricing than show it,
put
it in the comments. I'd love to see it.
And an FAQ section, D tier.
Frequently asked questions shouldn't have
its own section. It should be in the VSL.
In the VSL, you should objection handle.
You should know all the hesitations
and issues that people have about your
program.
You should put it in a video,
and you should answer it.
There shouldn't need to be an FAQ section
at the end.
And if you haven't clicked the link in the
description to get the anatomy of a
highly efficient landing page
or sales page,
then I recommend you do that now.
And if you're not interested in that,
you will be interested in this video
because
YouTube recommends
that you need to watch it.
I don't make the rules.
YouTube said it,
so you should do what YouTube says.